<tool name="bwa_index" version="0.6.2-r126">
	<description>
		Burrows-Wheeler Aligner (BWA) is an efficient program that 
		aligns relatively short nucleotide sequences against a long 
		reference sequence such as the human genome. It implements 
		two algorithms, bwa-short and BWA-SW. The former works for 
		query sequences shorter than 200bp and the latter for longer 
		sequences up to around 100kbp. Both algorithms do gapped 
		alignment. They are usually more accurate and faster on 
		queries with low error rates.
		
		Li H. and Durbin R. (2009) Fast and accurate short read 
		alignment with Burrows-Wheeler Transform. Bioinformatics, 
		25:1754-60. [PMID: 19451168]
		
		For both algorithms, the database file in the FASTA format 
		must be first indexed with the index command, which 
		typically takes a few hours. The first algorithm is 
		implemented via the aln command, which finds the suffix 
		array (SA) coordinates of good hits of each individual read, 
		and the samse/sampe command, which converts SA coordinates 
		to chromosomal coordinate and pairs reads (for sampe). The 
		second algorithm is invoked by the bwasw command. It works 
		for single-end reads only.
		
		** BWA Index database sequences in the FASTA format. **
		
		is IS linear-time algorithm for constructing suffix array. 
		It requires 5.37N memory where N is the size of the 
		database. IS is moderately fast, but does not work with 
		database larger than 2GB. IS is the default algorithm due to 
		its simplicity. The current codes for IS algorithm are 
		reimplemented by Yuta Mori. bwtsw Algorithm implemented in 
		BWT-SW. This method works with the whole human genome, but 
		it does not work with database smaller than 10MB and it is 
		usually slower than IS.
		
		Warning: "-a bwtsw" does not work for short genomes, while 
		"-a is" and "-a div" do not work not for long genomes. 
		Please choose "-a" according to the length of the genome. 
	</description>
	
	<inputs>
		<param name="input.fasta" type="file" label="Fasta reference(s)" >
			<help>Fasta file containing refrences sequences.</help>
		</param>
		
		<param name="param-a" type="string" label="Index creation method" optional="true">
			<cards min="1" max="1"/>
			<help>Algorithm used to build the index [is|bwtsw|auto]</help>
		</param>

<!--
		<param name="param-a" type="select" label="Index creation 
		algorithm" optional="true">
			<option value="is"> is </option> 
			<option value="auto" selected="True"> auto </option> 
			<option value="bwtsw"> bwtsw </option>
		</param>
-->

		<param name="param-p" type="string" label="Index id">
			<cards min="1" max="1"/>
			<help>Name of the generated index</help>
		</param>

	</inputs>

	<command>
		bwa_index_wrapper.sh
		 {?param-a 
		  -a {=param-a}}
		 {?param-p 
		  -p {=param-p}}
		 {?output.dir
			--pav-dir={=output.dir}}
		 {?input.fasta
		    --pav-ref={=input.fasta}}
	</command>

	<outputs>
		<param name="output.dir" type="directory" label="Index directory" >
			<cards min="1" max="1"/>
			<help>A directory containing the BWA index.</help>
		</param>
	</outputs>
	
</tool>
